Hare Krishna my dear sweet popsicles
welcome back to my YouTube channel
why am I slow [laughs]
sorry sorry Hare Krishna my dear sweet
popsicles welcome back to my YouTube channel
d popsicles so today I am going to share something really good with you
[nasal sound] and yes I
will not just babble there will be a
video after this but so let's
start.  So last
weekend, yes last weekend I was in office
and I could not shoot a video, so there was a huge
gap, so I thought
let's see, today I am going to shoot a video of mine and
post it, this is my second
video which I am shooting today and this
video is very special and today is Sunday and
this video is also very special, so let's
start, yes, I had told you [laughs]
that last weekend I was busy and
why I was busy, you must have understood by looking at my title.
Basically I participated in the event
and I work in ICICI
and I had to tell this thing or not.
You'll know that from my Lindin anyway.
So I'll
put my Lindin URL in my description.
Please go and follow me there
because whatever tech related things there are,
I post them on Lindin only.  Meaning, yes, yes,
true, I don't post.  But
I will try to share the good things
or the ineffective things.
So please follow me on Lindin.
And this video is going to be
very cool.  For freshers as well as
for those who are working.  So A
Guys my team Tech Titans has won.
Hackathon and it was a 36 hour hackathon.   Had
fun.  The team was very cool.  The team wasn't
just comprised of developers.  Was from the finance team.  The
operations team, banking team and
guys were very experienced.  I have
n't been there much time, but the
seniors in my team had a lot of
experience, and this is a huge advantage
because each team had nine use cases. There were
nine teams, everyone had a unique use
case. Basically, everyone had a business problem,
and everyone had to solve those problems.
We weren't tired at all in 36 hours.
We weren't tired at all. We didn't sleep,
literally, for an hour or an hour and a half. And
yet, our energy was at a
different level because everyone wanted to
solve and deliver whatever problem statement was there. Because, brother, it was a
matter of ego. There should
n't be any problem that we ca
n't solve. No matter how much AI comes, no matter what comes.
Guys, AI can't replace us. AI can't
replace us. [laughs] AI wo
n't be able to replace us because,
okay, it's a
mundane task or some
such task, so it takes your
time unnecessarily, but  If you can be more productive
then we can use AI technology
only so that we can be more productive
and whatever things are happening slowly, their pace can be
faster, that is why we use AI, so in this
hackathon we had to use AI
and we had to use Amazon's services in
which one of the major services
that we had to use was Bedrock Bedrock,
basically you can call it a service of AWS in
which there are multiple LLM models, by
using those models because
we had to give a solution of the use case.  So the
experience was very good for me.  My team was
very good.  It was not just my team, there were
nine teams and among all the teams, there was not a single
team who did
not propose their session on Monday.  Each team had its
own session.  And you know what the best part
was?  [nasal sound]
I think it's up to Mancom to
decide who the winner is.  This was going to be very
difficult because every
team's use case was very cool and every team had
created its session by Monday, so
somewhere I was also wondering who would win,
who would win, but you know the main thing is that
according to me all nine teams are winners, not
just according to me, but
according to everyone because everyone had worked very hard for
36 hours and they had delivered the session and
proposed it on Monday.
Even after working so rigorously, the energy on everyone's face on Monday was
unmatchable
[nasal sound], it was
unmatchable energy and you will not find this anywhere else, you will find it
in Labard, I don't know
because it is my first company and yes,
I have participated in hackathons before this,
which I did during my college days
and I had a very good experience
with Virtusa also and you
can go to my website and see how it was for us,
in which year I
participated. If you want more information, regarding how to
register and  How
to participate in hackathons and ideation
challenges
when you are in college is very easy.
Hacker Rank is there, go there.  There are
many companies there like Meta,
Virtus and Delit.  I think Google has them
too.  And what I saw there on Hacker
Rank was from Facebook
and I was not able to participate in it
because I had already participated in a hackathon
and I am not able to concentrate on two places.  I know that, that's why
I did not participate in it.
But it's there, there is a proper section
where you will find that hackathons or
edition challenges are happening.  And if you are
in college then please never miss this
opportunity because it will
help you a lot in the long term.  I participated
in college.  I had a very good
experience.  There was a lot of learning from experience, that's why
today I have been able to save here.  So
I was able to save it.  My team
also had a huge say in this because you
know what?  Ah, all the
nine teams of ours were
assigned one mentor each.  And I think the mentor who was
assigned was on the basis of the problem statement only.
Because as far as I know,
my mentor
knew everything about this problem statement.
Because whatever problems their team works on,
they faced on a regular daily basis,
our problem
statement was made from that.  And for us
it was literally for two days, Monday sorry Saturday Sunday.  Ah,
we got the use cases a day or two
before but we basically
created the PFR queue on Friday and from Saturday onwards we went into
proper discussion with it
[nasal sound] so
we were in the office for both the days, slept very little
but had a lot of fun and I think by the
entire Saturday evening we had properly
understood our use case and
prepared the architecture and then we
started the development and it was a great
experience, we enjoyed it, we got
to learn a lot because there were not only freshers in this team.  There were a
lot of experienced
people too and their experience has been very
useful to us, not only my team members but also
my managers who were
not in my team, guys.  But still whatever
experience he had, timely we
mean not only him but other
seniors also were roaming around the floor
and they were looking at everyone's solution and they were
also giving suggestions to them because you
know it was not just about Hackaton that this is a
team, so only this team will separate,
that team will separate, no brother, it was not like that, all the
seniors, as much as they could, were
going to every team and doing a
complete review and if in
case there was any lag, then they were
telling them that you can do it this way, you can do it
that way, so basically the team was just in
name.  We all were working in unity
and there is no one winner.  Everyone was a
winner.  But the experience was very good.
So if it doesn't happen at your place then please
propose and hackathons should happen
because hackathons are not just for winners or for that
because literally you are
solving business problems and if you
do it in as crisp a time as possible then
suppose a
problem statement has come, if it
comes normally on daily basis then you people do not solve it
with that much energy in that less crisp time,
okay it has come, CR
you are solving it, okay its
delivery date is this, it is like that but
if there is a change in this hackathon then
definitely there will be a lot of difference in productivity,
you will see that one thing happens
since childhood, when we
participate in any competition, then
before starting it there is a lot of energy and there is a
little fear also but when
we start those things then
in a very short time we use our brain so much that
we would not have done so much work even in 10 days.
So that thing
definitely helps a lot, so you should
participate, basically I would
like to tell this to the college students also that you will get a
lot of opportunities in the college, so
do DSA, its variety, but you should
also start working on real world real business problems.
Because if you
approach any company in future or
you want a job there, then this thing will
help you a lot.  So participate in hacktons.  No matter
how many books you
read or how many YouTube videos you
watch.  Unless you participate yourself,
you will
not get that experience.  That journey is
different.  So I want you guys to
start doing this, participate and have a lot of
fun.  Try participating once, you will
enjoy it a lot.  I have had a very good experience since my college days.
You know that through this one
also learns to work in a team.   I
mean, if you are working alone,
what will you do?  You will keep working on your own laptop as per your wish
and
you will not get any feedback from others.  But once you
start working with the team,
you will understand how the team actually
works.  Meaning you will have to listen to everyone's point of view.
You will have to take everyone's feedback.
If you have any idea,
suppose it is an idea.  Ok?  And you have
proposed that.  Right now you are working individually.
But if you work with a team, then
so many plus points will be added to that idea, then it will become
so good from A to A plus plus plus plus plus.
So you will also learn to work with a team
and start these things from college.
Now I will not bore you much.
My experience was very good.
I enjoyed it.  You follow me on Lindin
and after this, the video that is going to come,
I have
taken small clips.  I can't
explain much.  I cannot tell you
because there are some restrictions.
And I hope you will understand this.  End
is fine.  Whatever little clips
etc. I have taken, please watch them and enjoy them.  Bye bye.
Hare Krishna.
This is Saturday Sunday so today is Saturday.  So that's why
I'm back.  But today we have come
in very cool attire.  So let
me show you the dress.
[Music]
Hello Pickles, we have won and this
girl was crying when we were receiving the award
[laughs]
don't do this, friend, don't do this, we have come to Marine Drive
and in Jyoti, we both were in the same team and
our colleague Sanjay is going to explain the entire process to him,
what we did and what we did
n't do, so we
came here just to sit and roam around, we were feeling a little good, so let me
show you a little part of them.
Hi, we have come here to have
fun and also to celebrate.
Tell someone first time gin
is okay.  So hello popsicles.  So it has been
one and a half hour since we have been sitting at Marine Drive.
So we thought we should
explore the surrounding area.  I will come after eating.
So we are going to eat Rustom Ice Creams.
Ice cream lovers?  Rustam is
going to eat ice cream.  So see you.